# HIMADRI S TEWARI

Louisville, KY +15027627127 himadri4uster@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/himadri-sekhar-tewari github.com/hstewari

## **Summary**

Over 13 years of professional experience working in all phases of Software Development Lifecycle in the information technology and services industry. Diversified experience in Data Validation, Business Analysis, Requirements Analysis, Agile Methodologies, Global Delivery & Quality Engineering. 7 years of rich experience in QSR industry. Data enthusiast and currently undergoing Master's degree focused on Applied Data Science from Syracuse University.

## **Skills**

### Technical Skills

R, SQL, Python, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MS Access, Advanced Excel, pgAdmin, ZOC, TOAD, MS-SQL server management Studio, draw.io, Tableau, Google Analytics, RStudio, Weka, XLSTAT, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Numpy, Pandas, nltk, sklearn, sci-kit,wordcloud, matplotlib, ggplot2, dplyr, rpart, naivebayes, corrplot, arules, cluster, arulesviz, Association Rule Mining, Decision Tree, Naïve Bayes, SVM, Text Mining, Topic Modeling, NLP, K-means Cluster, Random Forest, Azure DevOps, JIRA-ZEPHYR, HP Quality Center, TFS, Microsoft SharePoint, VSTS, IBM Telelogic DOORS, Clear Quest, Trello, Bugzilla, Squids, Compuware TestPartner and Selenium, Conceptual Model, Normalized Logical Model, GUI Prototype using R, SPSS

## Management Skill

3+ years of Agile/Scrum experience & guided team in Agile implementation. Estimation, budgeting, and forecasting of effort and cost for Projects. Experience in onshore-offshore project model and multiple vendor team structure. Trained project members in Business applications, Process & Testing Methodologies. Bring in innovation and process improvement in projects. Experience in RFPs and SOWs. Excellent written and verbal communication skills.

## Academic Project Experience

May 2019 - June 2019 Analysis of Employee Reviews: Google, Amazon, Facebook, Apple, and Microsoft

IST 736 - Text Mining

In this project, we have done data preprocessing and data analysis to analyze Review Count per Company per Year, Review Count per Employee Type, Overall Rating per Employee Type, Average Stars per Company Heatmap, Word Cloud to show the Pros and Cons for each Company. We have used Supervised Learning, Textual Classification and Sentiment Analysis methods and applied Naive Bayes and Support Vector Machines models to analyze whether a model can learn from the data to correctly recognize the employee attitude based on pure textual information

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019 Impact of HbA1c on Hospital Readmission Rates

IST 707 - Data Analytics

In this project, we have done data analysis to analyze the factors which impact the readmission rates. We have created a correlation matrix to understand the relation between the numeric variables. We have also used the K-means clustering method to group similar objects together in a cluster. We have applied Association Rule Mining technique by applying the apriori algorithm to find the frequent pattern, correlation or causal structure from the dataset. We have applied different classification techniques like Decision Tree, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machine and calculates the accuracy rate, error rate, and confusion matrix. To analyze text data, we have used SnowballC package is used for document stemming.

Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

## Predicting the price using Boston Housing dataset

## IST 687 - Applied Data Science

To predict the median value (MEDV) of homes using 13 Census-related variables from Boston Housing dataset, we have done Exploratory Data Analysis. We have created the Multiple Linear Regression, Random Forest and Multiple Logistic Regression model and calculate the accuracy, error rate and confusion matrix

Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

## Database for an Online Pizza Company

## IST659 – Data Admin Concepts & Database Management

Build a database for a pizza company for online ordering application. I have created the Entities and the Attributes, Conceptual Model, Normalized Logical Model and various SQL DDL commands to create tables using create table, stored procedure to create tables, view, insert statements. SQL DML select statements. I have used R to create bar chart to compare the Guest vs Registered Customer

## Work Experience

Feb 2007 - Till Date

Senior Associate - Projects

Cognizant Technology Solutions

July 2006 - Jan 2007

Graduate Trainee Engineer (Instruments)

Shyam Sel Limited (Power Division)

## **Project Experience**

Jun 2019 - Till Date

### **Business Analyst**

#### KFC US

- Coordinating with Business Stakeholders and Operations to understand business vision and providing solutions for the overall system.
- Creating User Journey flow, Business Process Model and Business documents for an existing application and to-be features by collaborating with Stakeholders and UX/VD team.
- Identifying and documenting functional and non-functional requirements with appropriate solutions.
- Creating Features and User Stories describing the functional and non-functional requirements in Azure DevOps.
- Leading all required Agile ceremonies Daily Scrum meeting, Backlog Grooming session, Sprint Planning session, Sprint Demo session.
- Conducting Sync-up discussion with all teams to make sure everyone has a clear understanding of the business vision and needs.
- Assisting and coordinating with all the groups for the best solutions or decisions about any issues or problems.
- Assisting Stakeholders and In-Sprint team members by creating metrics and queries in Azure DevOps.

#### Feb 2019 - Jun 2019

## POS & Digital Consultant

## Papa John's International

- Process consultant & SME of the POS application; understand the need for Client and providing solutions
- Data modeling and Validation using PostgreSQL of new functionality and provide suggestions based on the experience of whole application architecture.

#### Mar 2018 - Feb 2019

## Program Test Manager

#### Humana

- Manage, and guide the Quality Engineering team
- Created business documentation like Master Test Strategy, Gap Analysis, Project Estimation, Requirements Gap Analysis, Effort & Resource Estimation
- Publish monthly KPI, discuss the numbers with Client and take corrective actions to improve DRE and overall KPI.

## May 2012 - Mar 2018

## Sr. QE&A Lead

## Papa John's International

- Forecasting & Scheduling Quality Engineering (QE) activities throughout the Project Lifecycle.
- Manage, guide and lead the onsite team and offshore team of more than 8 members.
- Quality Engineering of POS application & Data validation with PostgreSQL scripts

## Feb 2012 - Jan 2008

## Sr. QA Lead

Multiple Clients like Pizza Hut, Mass Mutual, Title Resource Group, Family Dollar

- Analyze and prepare business requirement document, Test Strategy, Plan and Estimate for the project.
- Handle testing during production deployment and prepare the project summary report.
- Involved in the development of the Automation framework, scripting, and execution for Automation Testing for Retail POS.
- Involved in Functional Testing, Database Validation of migrated data, System Integration, and Regression testing by executing test cases in Quality Center. Handled Project Management and Project Tracking activities.
- Assigned tasks to team members and tracking those in TFS, involved in creating Requirement Traceability Matrix, Test design, execution, data management and keeping track of the defects and change requests in the Defect Management System (C2.0)

### Education

| 2018 - 2019 | Masters of Science (Masters) - Applied Data Science  Syracuse University   |
|-------------|--|
| 2002 - 2006 | Bachelor of Technology (Bachelors) - Electronics & Instrumentation Engineering<br>West Bengal University of Technology |
| 2008 - 2012 | Post Graduate Diploma in Business Management - Human Resource  Symbiosis Centre For Distance Learning                  |